# Muhammad Alkali Muawiya

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a highly motivated and dedicated individual with robust knowledge of agile methodologies, particularly scrum. I have experience working remotely and understand the importance of good communication. With strong problem-solving skills and efficient time management, I have designed and implemented software solutions for various business needs. My expertise lies in Node.js development, and I have a successful track record in industries such as healthcare and entertainment. As a proactive engineer and leader, I excel in collaborative environments and bring a strong work ethic to every task.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Decagon, Lagos Nigeria — Software Engineer

JUNE 2020 - Date

- Developed and maintained web applications using web development concepts such as HTTP, REST, GraphQL, and MVC architecture, utilizing TypeScript to write clean, efficient, and well-documented code.
- Built and managed databases using database management systems such as SQL and MongoDB.
- Implemented DevOps tools and methodologies such as Docker to improve application deployment and scalability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams including product managers, designers, and other developers to build new features and enhance existing ones.
- Ensured the performance, security, and reliability of web applications by implementing best practices and testing strategies and staying up-to-date with emerging trends, technologies, and development practices in the web development field.

# Techvibes International Ltd, Abuja Nigeria — User Experience

JUNE 2019 - JUNE 2020

- Gathered and wrote reports on product requirements for software, ensuring clear understanding of client needs and specifications.
- Conducted quality assessments of products by identifying and documenting problems, working closely with the technical team to propose effective solutions.
- Monitored and reported users' reactions and feedback after launching software, allowing for continuous improvement and enhancement of user experience.
- Provided support and training to both internal and external users, ensuring their successful utilization of the software and addressing any questions or issues they encountered.

## **ADDRESS**

Nepa Close, Off Ahmadu Bello Way, Victoria Island, 101241, Lagos Nigeria.

+2347060702020

muawiyamuhd@gmail.com LinkedIn Profile URL Github Profile URL Portfolio URL

#### TECHNOLOGIES & SKILLS

- Node.js
- Express.js
- React.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Docker
- SQL
- MongoDB
- GraphQL
- REST API
- Git & Github
- Teams
- Slack
- Jira
- Scrum

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

## Appen, UK (Remote) — Freelancer

FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

### **Search Engine Evaluator**

- Evaluated and analyzed search engine results based on specific guidelines and criteria.
- Provided feedback on the accuracy and relevance of search engine algorithms and results.
- Stayed updated with the latest search engine trends and guidelines to improve evaluation accuracy.

## **Social Media Evaluator**

- Assessed and evaluated the quality and relevance of social media content and advertisements.
- Provided feedback on social media trends, user behavior, and engagement to enhance algorithms and ad targeting.
- Identified and reported any content or policy violations observed during the evaluation process.

# Transcriptionist

- Accurately transcribing audio or video content while following transcription guidelines.
- Maintaining high-quality transcripts with accurate grammar, punctuation, and formatting.
- Meeting project deadlines and productivity targets while ensuring attention to detail and maintaining confidentiality.

# **PROJECTS**

## E-Aid

E-Aid(a First-Aid app) allows users to have access to verified medical experts through the app. It will allow the users to see hospitals closest to them and help them to get expert advice in the case of an emergency. Technologies used include: Express.js, Typescript, MySQL, Sequelize, React, AWS, Docker, Cloudinary, Nodemailer, CSS3. Link: <a href="https://e-aid-66j7.onrender.com">https://e-aid-66j7.onrender.com</a>

## MovieVerse

MovieVerse is a movie listing app where registered users can add, edit and delete movies with titles, images, prices and brief descriptions. It offers a user-friendly interface to manage the movie list easily. Technologies used include: Express.js, Typescript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Docker, EJS. Link: https://movie-verse.onrender.com

# My Portfolio

A responsive Single Page Application that showcases my skills and projects as a software developer. Technologies used include; HTML, CSS and Vanilla JavaScript. **Link**: https://www.mmalkali.me

#### **EDUCATION**

# Modibbo Adama University of Technology, Yola Nigeria

DECEMBER 2012 - MAY 2019

First Class Honours - Bachelor of Technology (Hons) in Biochemistry Best Graduating Student of the Department and Faculty, 2017/2018

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Docker for the absolute beginner Credential
- Introduction to Cyber Security
- EF SET English Proficiency Credential
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) Credential
- Accelerated Jobberman Soft Skills Credential